# **Hallo Rizgar**

LinkedIn: <u>Linkedin.com/in/hallo-rzgar</u>
GitHub: <u>Github.com/hallo-rzgar</u>
Email: <u>hallorzgar99@qmail.com</u>

Erbil, Iraq +964 (0)750 342 3581 Portfolio: <u>hallo-rizgar</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

Results-driven and motivated Software Engineer with demonstrated experience in improving software performance, testing, and updating existing software with +3 years of knowledge in back-end development from information gathering, planning, database design, development, testing, and deployment and maintenance.

· Expertise: Back-End Engineering, Database Engineering, Requirement Engineering, Communication Skills, Team Leader

#### **EDUCATION**

B.S. Bachelor of Science in Software and Informatics Engineering. – Salahaddin University, 2017- 2022 rank.1st

#### SKILLS

Laravel, PHP, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL Git, AWS, AWS SQS, JavaScript, React.js, jQuery, AJAX, Slim, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Full Stack Developer Jiasaz, Erbil, Iraq January 2022 - Present

- I've joined Jiasaz as a full-stack developer to develop, maintain and optimize different parts of Jiasaz's systems like: medical management system, school system and Global Cargo Systems
- during the period of my employment, I was not focused on a single component but rather on doing tasks from both ends (front end, back end) from multiple parts of Jiasaz.
- At first, I was mainly Back-end Focused that I designed database ERDs for new features, and query optimization for some queries and I was improving their customer service system UI.
- then, I started to work on the jiasaz Pay project from both ends. I built the Admin dashboard from scratch and I was reviewing and testing the back-end.
- Managing a passionate team to deliver & building clients' projects and requests in the most efficient way.
- Code review and Task distribution also making ensuring that tasks have been handled correctly.
- Support customers directly to do their requirements and solve problems
- Finally, I started to work on Jiasaz's Dispatching system. I was maintaining, Optimizing, Revamping, and adding features to a Microservice architecture-oriented Application from both ends.
- **Skills:** PHP · Laravel · Testing · Slim · MySQL · jQuery · AJAX · Amazon SQS

# Backend developer Homele, Erbil, Iraq February 2021 – June 2022

- I was a Core Developer of building APIs of a Real-estate Management system and Part of multiple management systems in Accounting, Property, and inventory domains.
- One of my new responsibilities was Requirement Engineering to be a bridge between development and the business.
- As working on the management systems as a back-end developer, I was also the **main front-end developer to build** the dashboards and integration with the backend.
- After a while, I was taking more responsibility to fill our company's needs and I was stepping up into another position of full stack developer.
- Skills: DevOps · Laravel · jQuery ·AJAX · MySQL.

### Backend developer Artvit Company, Erbil, Iraq September 2020 – February 2021

- Started my career life with a Artvit company, I started as a back-end developer to develop, maintain and optimize Artvit's systems.
- I was mainly focused on building APIs to develop highly dynamic systems.
- Collaborating with the front-end team to ensure integration between both ends.
- · At the same time, I was maintaining some previous made APIs for any new feature or bug fixes.
- After a while, I was taking more responsibility to fill our company's needs and I was stepping up into another position of full stack developer.
- **Skills:** Laravel · MySQL · JavaScript · jQuery.

# **Back-end Developer & DevOps Freelancer Work 2019 - Present**

- Worked as a Team or individually to develop Rest API for multiple Projects.
- I did Requirement gathering and Project Overview during this period.
- **Skills:** Git · DevOps · Laravel · PHP · Express.js · jQuery ·AJAX · MySQL · MongoDB · PostgreSQL.